BRICE A. HUISKEN

372 South Grant Street | Denver, CO 80209 (303) 521-5956 | brice.huisken@gmail.com

SOLUTION MINDED PROFESSIONAL

Accomplished Marketing and Advertising Technology professional with extensive experience developing and implementing solutions in support of key organizational goals and objectives. Able to build strong relationships with key internal and external business partners through the delivery of exceptional service to drive increases in customer satisfaction, retention and overall sales. Unique in the ability to combine technical expertise with interpersonal skills to deliver exceptional results in fast-paced, challenging environments.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Customer Relationship Management
- Email Service Providers
- Personalization

- Project Management
- Web Analytics
- Solution Architecture
- Campaign Orchestration
- Integrations
- Quality Assurance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SEGMENT, DENVER, CO

Solution Architect (2019 – Present)

2019 - Present

- Lead technical onboarding engagements of Segment Customer Data Platform with Commercial and Enterprise companies.
- Work daily with customers, CSMs, and developers to make sure new customers are trained and have what they need
 to effectively use Segment products

MERKLE, INC., DENVER, CO

2017 - 2019

Platform Architect (2017 – 2019)

- Unique hybrid of business and technical consultant with the ability to operate as a digital tech lead focusing on the Oracle Responsys Platform.
- Responsible for the successful onboarding and overall technological direction for Oracle Responsys customers.
- Works as a liaison between the account management and operations team to design and deliver high quality, scalable technical solutions.
- Architects data feeds, platform configuration, and components needed to run complex automated email campaigns.
- Acts as a SME in implementing Dynamic Content via RPL scripting and/or Responsys Email Message Designer.
- Lead integrations with 3rd party platforms such as Certona, LiveClicker, Segment, and others.
- Lead and architected large-scale project with a major Retail client to scale and automate highly personalized email messages.

ORACLE CLOUD SERVICES, DENVER, CO

2013 - 2017

Senior Sales Consultant (2015 – 2017)

- Prepare and deliver solution timely presentations and product demonstrations, providing detailed qualification of opportunities, formulation of sales strategies and technical approaches and plans.
- Propose marketing automation solutions to both enterprise and mid-market prospects in a dynamic, challenging market.
- Develop and deliver high quality Oracle Marketing Cloud presentations and demonstrations, encompassing Responsys, BlueKai, Maxymiser, SRM, Compendium and Datalogix. Initiate Product, Discovery, Competitive Intel, and Cross Platform enablement to Enterprise and Mid-Market prospects.
- Conduct Technical Discovery sessions directly with prospects and customers.
- Recognized by Business Development for going above and beyond support for business development & sales relations.

Product Consultant (2013 – 2015)

- Successfully led the onboarding effort around new general business clients from multiple verticals to the Responsys email platform.
- Served as a subject matter expert and trusted advisor, assisting clients with switching email service providers with a focus on process, service, speed, and meeting the needs of multiple stakeholders and client-side teams.

BRICE HUISKEN Resume, Page 2

Professional Experience Continued

- Mentored clients on platform usage and data and API integrations, as well as coordinated, tracked and monitored general technical onboarding activities.
- Maintained responsibility for ad-hoc projects including the lifecycle program implementation, analytics integration, and unsubscribe/preference center forms.

EPSILON DATA MANAGEMENT, LAFAYETTE, CO

2009 - 2013

Lead Business Solutions Analyst, Digital (BSA)

- Build highly advanced platform-related solutions for full service clients.
- Manage all aspects of complex projects including scope, specification documentation, campaign/program set-up, creation of test plans, quality assurance/use acceptable testing, program launch and post deployment analysis.
- Consulted for clients, evaluating requirements translated into cutting edge, forward thinking solutions.
- Oversee cross-functional builds for clients, Client Services and Technology leads.
- Played a key role as a team representative tasked with assisting in the design process for a highly visible email/display advertising retargeting product.
- Successfully created a program that effectively surveyed team members to identify Subject Matter Experts (SME) and led to a reduction in project turn-around times when the SME was assigned and/or consulted on projects.
- Maintained a 100% error-free rate in terms of project builds and campaign deployments.

GOOGLE / DOUBLECLICK, INC. - THORNTON, CO

2001 - 2009

Team Leader - Rich Media Production Services (2007 - 2009)

- Led a team consisting of 8 Rich Media Production Service Specialists, delegating work to an offshore team of 21 to help meet tight deadlines and serving as the main point-of-contact for all technical matters and escalations.
- Accurately analyzed the complexity of client's Rich Media assets, determining the turnaround time and assigning developers to convert client assets into DCRM format.
- Facilitated strong working relationships with Campaign Managers, Quality Assurance, Strategy and the Sales teams.
- Tracked client success through Rich Media Campaign metrics, addressing client needs based on the results obtained.
- Developed highly complex Rich Media ads or ads with special functionality with assistance from the strategy and escalation teams.

Rich Media Production Services Specialist (2006 – 2007)

- Successfully converted client's Rich Media Ads into DCRM creative using Ad kits and Macromedia Flash on Windows and MAC.
- Implemented tracking metrics and functionality to client's ads through the use of ActionScript.
- Analyzed, revised and improved client's ActionScript Code.
- Performed unit testing and quality analysis within DFA and the lie environment across multiple browsers and operating systems.
- Worked in collaboration with Product Management, providing input to improve DCRM products.
- Accurately documented client-facing technical processes to be more understandable for non-technical clients, which allowed for easier and more efficient product use.
- Provided technical expertise to sales and pre-sales communication with prospective clients.

Previous Employment: Rich Media Campaign Manager (2004 – 2005), Senior Technical Account Manager (2002 – 2004), Client Service Analyst (CSA) (2001 – 2002) – Google/DoubleClick, Inc.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

Marketing Technology: Segment, Oracle Marketing Cloud, Web Analytics

Other Technology: HTML, JavaScript and JS Frameworks, CSS and CSS Frameworks, SQL, REST APIs, Video Production

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Technical Communications - Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp - University of Denver, Denver, CO